Guide to the Clippings File of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal/Corporate Names, Series II
  - Knight, Gladys (Box 109)
  - Knoxville College (Box 109)
  - Kotto, Yaphet (Box 109)
  - Krigwa Players (Box 109)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 109)
  - Lam, Wifredo (Box 110)
  - Lamming, George (Box 110)
  - Langston University (Box 110)
  - Larsen, Nella (Box 110)
  - Lawless, Theodore K. (Box 110)
  - Lawrence, Jacob, 1938-1949; 2 (Box 110)
  - Ledbetter, Huddie (Leadbelly) (Box 110)
  - Lee, Canada, 1935-1947; 3 (Box 111)
  - Lee, Don L. (Box 111)
  - Lee, Everett (Box 111)
  - Lee, Leslie (Box 111)
  - Lee-Smith, Hughie (Box 111)
  - LeNoire, Rosetta (Box 111)
  - Lester, Julius (Box 111)
  - Lewis, Henry (Box 111)
  - Liberation Committee for Africa (Box 112)
  - Lincoln, Abbey (Box 112)
  - Abraham Lincoln School (Box 112)
  - Lincoln University (Pennsylvania), 1885-1955; 3 (Box 112)
  - Lincoln University (Pennsylvania) (continued), 1956-1962, undated; 4 (Box 113)
  - Liston, Sonny (Box 113)
  - Little, Cleavon (Box 113)
  - Little, John (Box 113)
  - Locke, Alain (Box 114)
  - Logan, Arthur C. (Box 114)
  - Logan, Rayford W. (Box 114)
  - Lomax, Louis E. (Box 114)
  - Long, Avon (Box 114)
  - Louis, Joe, 1935-1938; 4 (Box 114)
  - Louis, Joe (continued), 1939-1959; 6 (Box 115)
  - Lyon, Leviticus (Box 116)
  - Mabley, Jackie (Moms) (Box 116)
  - McClendon, Rose (Box 116)
  - McDaniel, Hattie (Box 116)
  - McFerrin, Robert (Box 116)
  - McKayle, Donald (Box 116)
  - Mackey, William Wellington (Box 116)
  - McKinney, Nina Mae (Box 116)
  - McRae, Carmen (Box 116)
  - McNeil, Claudia (Box 116)
  - McQueen, Butterfly (Box 116)
  - Major, Clarence (Box 116)
  - Marchant, Claude (Box 116)
  - Markham, Pigmeat (Box 116)
  - Marr, Warren, II (Box 116)
  - Marriott, John (Box 116)
  - Makeba, Miriam (Box 116)
  - Marshall, Paule (Box 117)
  - Marshall, Thurgood, 1947-1967; 2 (Box 117)
  - Marshall, William (Box 117)
  - Saint Martín de Porres (Box 117)
  - Masses and Mainstream (Box 117)
  - Mathis, Johnny (Box 117)
  - Maudelle (Box 117)
  - Mayfield, Julian (Box 117)
  - Maynor, Dorothy, 1939-1951; 5 (Box 118)
  - Mays, Benjamin E. (Box 118)
  - Mays, Willie, 1951-1972; 3 (Box 118)
  - Meadows, Jerome (Box 119)
  - Meeres, Paul (Box 119)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis (Box 119)
  - Mercer, Mabel (Box 119)
  - Meredith, James, 1962-1963; 3 (Box 119)
  - Michaux, Elder Lightfoot Solomon (Box 119)
  - Michaux, Lewis (Box 119)
  - Millican, Arthenia J. Bates, 1980 (Box 120)
  - Milner, Ron (Box 120)
  - Mills, Florence (Box 120)
  - Mingus, Charlie (Box 120)
  - Mississippi Vocational College (Itta Bene) (Box 120)
  - Mitchell, Abbie (Box 120)
  - Mitchell, Arthur, 1956-1967; 6 (Box 121)
  - Mitchell, Howard (Box 121)
  - Mitchell, Loften (Box 121)
  - Mittelholzer, Edgar (Box 121)
  - Modern Community Developers, Inc. (Box 122)
  - Modern Jazz Quartet (Box 122)
  - Modern School of Harlem (Box 122)
  - Moncion, Francisco (Box 122)
  - Monk, Thelonious (Box 122)
  - Monroe Defense Committee (Box 122)
  - Moore, Archie (Box 122)
  - Moore, Eulabelle (Box 122)
  - Moore, Melba (Box 122)
  - Moral Re-Armament (Box 122)
  - Morgan State College (Box 122)
  - Morehouse College (Box 122)
  - Morris, Greg (Box 123)
  - Morrison, Toni (Box 123)
  - Morrow, Everett Frederick (Box 123)
  - Morton, Ferdinand (Jelly Roll) (Box 123)
  - Moses, Gilbert (Box 123)
  - Motley, Archibald (Box 123)
  - Motley, Constance Baker (Box 123)
  - Motley, Willard (Box 123)
  - Moton, Robert Russa (Box 123)
  - Mphalele, Ezekiel (Box 123)
  - Mulzac, Hugh (Box 123)
  - Murray, Albert (Box 123)
  - Murray, Pauli (Box 123)
  - Muse, Clarence (Box 123)
  - Museum of Black History and Culture (New York City) (Box 123)
  - Myers, Pauline (Box 123)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar (Box 123)
  - Nail, John B. (Box 124)
  - Nail, John E. (Box 124)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
    - General, 1914-1933, undated; 5 (Box 124)
    - General (continued), 1933-1950; 6 (Box 125)
    - General (continued), 1951-1960; 6 (Box 126)
    - General (continued), 1960-1970; 6 (Box 127)
    - General (continued), 1970-1972; 2 (Box 128)
    - Legal Defense and Educational Fund (Box 128)
    - Committee of 100 (Box 128)
    - New York Branch (Box 128)
    - College and Local Branches (Box 128)
  - National Association of Colored Graduate Nurses (Box 129)
  - National Association of Dramatic Speech Arts (Box 129)
  - National Association of Negro Musicians, 1946-1952; 2 (Box 129)
  - National Catholic Conference for Interracial Justice (Box 129)
  - National Citizens Political Action Committee (Box 129)
  - National Civil Liberties Clearing House (Box 129)
  - National Committee to Abolish the Poll Tax (Box 129)
  - National Committee to Defend Negro Leadership (Box 129)
  - National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims, 1951-1954; 2 (Box 129)
  - National Conference of Jews and Christians (Institute of Human Relations, Williams College) (Box 130)
  - National Conference of Negro Youth (Box 130)
  - National Council for Culture and Arts (Box 130)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (Box 130)
  - National Council of Negro Women (Box 130)
  - National Council of Negro Youth (Box 130)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions (Box 130)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (Box 130)
  - National Negro Congress (Box 130)
  - National Negro Opera Company (Box 130)
  - National Non-Partisan Committee to Defend the Rights of the 12 Communist Leaders (Box 130)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc. (Box 130)
  - National Union of Marine Cooks and Stewards (Box 130)
  - National Urban League
    - General, 1925-1962; 5 (Box 131)
    - General (continued), 1963-1970; 2 (Box 132)
    - National Urban League Guild, 1942-1961; 3 (Box 132)
    - Urban League of Greater New York (Box 132)
    - Chicago Urban League (Box 133)
    - Miscellaneous Local Branches (Box 133)
  - Negro Actors Guild, 1938-1952; 4 (Box 133)
  - Negro Actors Guild (continued), 1953-1960; 2 (Box 134)
  - Negro Art (Box 134)
  - Negro Art Players (Box 134)
  - Negro Book Club (Box 134)
  - Negro Dance Company (Box 134)
  - Negro Ensemble Company, 1967-1971; 2 (Box 134)
  - Negro Heritage Library (Box 134)
  - Negro Playwrights Company (Box 134)
  - New Masses (Box 135)
  - New World Review (Box 135)
  - New York Amsterdam News (Box 135)
  - New York Council on the Arts, Sciences, and Professions, 1947-1951; 2 (Box 135)
  - New York Intercultural Society (Box 135)
  - New York Shakespeare Festival (Box 135)
  - New York Society for Ethical Culture (Box 135)
  - New York State Conference of Negro Youth (Box 135)
  - Norman, Jessye (Box 135)
  - Norton, Eleanor Holmes (Box 135)
  - Odetta (Box 136)
  - Okala, Ollie Sims (Box 136)
  - Olanf (Box 136)
  - Olatunji, Michael Babatunde (Box 136)
  - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, 1930-1962, undated; 5 (Box 136)
  - One World Ensemble (Box 137)
  - O'Neal, Frederick, 1945-1963; 2 (Box 137)
  - O'Neal, Ron (Box 137)
  - Operation Crossroads Africa (Box 137)
  - Opportunity: A Journal of Negro Life (Box 137)
  - Ottley, Roi (Box 137)
  - Ovington, Mary White (Box 137)
  - Ouologuem, Yambo (Box 137)
  - Owens, Jesse (Box 137)
  - Paige, Satchel (Box 138)
  - Palfi, Marion (Box 138)
  - Palmer Memorial Institute (Box 138)
  - Pankey, Aubrey (Box 138)
  - Parker, Charlie (Box 138)
  - Parks, Gordon, 1950-1971; 2 (Box 138)
  - Parkway Community House (Chicago) (Box 138)
  - Paton, Alan, 1948-1958; 2 (Box 138)
  - Patterson, Floyd, 1954-1962; 2 (Box 139)
  - Patterson, Massie (The Carib Singers) (Box 139)
  - Patterson, William L. (Box 139)
  - Peabody College (Box 139)
  - Peace Information Center (Box 139)
  - Pele (Box 139)
  - Penthouse Dance and Drama Theatre (Box 139)
  - Peters, Brock (Box 139)
  - Peterson, Dorothy R. (Box 139)
  - Peterson, Jerome Bowers (Box 139)
  - Peterson, Jerome Sidney (Box 139)
  - Peterson, Louis (Box 139)
  - Petry, Ann (Box 140)
  - Pharr, Robert Deane (Box 140)
  - Pickens, William (Box 140)
  - Pierre-Noel, Lois M. Jones (Box 140)
  - Piney Woods Country Life School, 1944-1961; 2 (Box 140)
  - Pinero, Miguel (Box 140)
  - Pippin, Horace (Box 140)
  - Poitier, Sidney, 1950-1961; 2 (Box 140)
  - Poitier, Sidney (continued), 1964-1969; 4 (Box 141)
  - Police Athletic League (Box 141)
  - Polk, Oscar (Box 141)
  - Polk, P. H. (Box 141)
  - Porter, James A. (Box 141)
  - Poston, Ersa (Box 141)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1937-1967; 7 (Box 142)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr. (continued), 1967-1972; 5 (Box 143)
  - Powell, Bud (Box 143)
  - Premice, Josephine (Box 144)
  - Preservation Hall Jazz Band (Box 144)
  - Press Club of New York City (Box 144)
  - Price, Gilbert (Box 144)
  - Price, Leontyne, 1946-1959; 4 (Box 144)
  - Price, Leontyne (continued), 1960-1962; 6 (Box 145)
  - Price, Leontyne (continued), 1962-1967; 5 (Box 146)
  - Primus, Pearl, 1943-1948; 2 (Box 147)
  - Prosser, Gabriel (Box 147)
  - Pushkin, Alexander (Box 147)
  - Rahn, Muriel, 1941-1950; 3 (Box 147)
  - Randall, Dudley (Box 147)
  - Randolph, Asa Philip, 1930-1972; 2 (Box 148)
  - Raspberry, William (Box 148)
  - Reading, Bertice (Box 148)
  - Redding, Jay Saunders (Box 148)
  - Reed, Ishmael (Box 148)
  - Reese, Della (Box 148)
  - Repertory Playhouse Associates (Box 148)
  - Richards, Lloyd (Box 148)
  - Richer, Clement (Box 148)
  - Riley, Clayton (Box 148)
  - Rivers, Francis E. (Box 148)
  - Robeson, Eslanda Goode (Box 149)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1922-1942; 6 (Box 149)
  - Robeson, Paul (continued), 1943-1957; 6 (Box 150)
  - Robeson, Paul (continued), 1958-1960; 2 (Box 151)
  - Robinson, Bill, 1925-1949; 3 (Box 151)
  - Robinson, Jackie, 1945-1972; 5 (Box 152)
  - Robinson, James H. (Box 152)
  - Robinson, Sugar Ray, 1941-1953; 2 (Box 152)
  - Rogers, Richard (Box 152)
  - Rolle, Esther (Box 153)
  - Rollins, Sonny (Box 153)
  - Rome, H. J. (Box 153)
  - (Julius) Rosenwald Fund (Box 153)
  - Ross, Diana (Box 153)
  - Roumain, Jacques (Box 153)
  - Roundtree, Richard (Box 153)
  - Rowan, Carl T., 1951-1968; 3 (Box 153)
  - Rowan, Carl T. (continued), 1969-1972; 6 (Box 154)
  - Rowan, Carl T. (continued), 1973-1986; 6 (Box 155)
  - Rudd, Wayland (Box 155)
  - Rushing, Jimmy (Box 155)
  - Russell, Bill (Box 155)
  - Russell, Nipsey (Box 155)
  - Rust College (Box 155)
  - Rustin, Bayard (Box 155)
  - St. Jacques, Raymond (Box 156)
  - Sampson, Edith (Box 156)
  - Sands, Diana, 1957-1965; 2 (Box 156)
  - Savage, Augusta (Box 156)
  - Schomburg, Arthur (Box 156)
  - Schomburg Collection - New York Public Library, Countee Cullen Branch, 1926-1966 (Box 156)
  - Schomburg Collection - New York Public Library, Countee Cullen Branch (continued), 1967-1975 (Box 157)
  - Schuyler, George, 1926-1958 (Box 157)
  - Schuyler, Philippa Duke, 1931-1955; 4 (Box 157)
  - Schuyler, Philippa Duke (continued), 1955-1967; 4 (Box 158)
  - Philippa Schuyler Memorial Foundation (Box 158)
  - Schweitzer, Albert (Box 158)
  - Scott, Emmett J. (Box 158)
  - Scott, Harold (Box 158)
  - Scott, Hazel, 1942-1955; 2 (Box 158)
  - Scottsboro Case (Box 159)
  - Seale, Bobby (Box 159)
  - Shange, Ntozake (Box 159)
  - Shaw, Nate (Box 159)
  - Shine, Ted (Box 159)
  - Shirley, Don (Box 159)
  - Shirley, George, 1961-1967; 2 (Box 159)
  - Short, Bobby (Box 159)
  - Silvera, Frank, 1947-1960; 2 (Box 160)
  - Simms, Hilda (Box 160)
  - Simone, Nina (Box 160)
  - Simpson, Orenthal James (Box 160)
  - Sissle, Noble (Box 160)
  - Smith, Bessie (Box 160)
  - Smith, Lillian (Box 160)
  - Smith, Muriel, 1941-1956; 2 (Box 161)
  - Societe Africaine de Culture (Box 161)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference (Box 161)
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund, 1947-1956; 2 (Box 161)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare (Box 161)
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress (Box 161)
  - Southern University (Box 161)
  - Sowande, Fela (Box 161)
  - Soyinka, Wole (Box 161)
  - Spearman, Rawn (Box 162)
  - Spelman College (Box 162)
  - Spencer, Anne (Box 162)
  - Spencer, Kenneth (Box 162)
  - Spingarn, Arthur (Box 162)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. (Box 162)
  - Stage Door Canteen (Box 162)
  - Stevens, Harold A. (Box 162)
  - Stewart, Ellen (Box 162)
  - Stewart, Melvin (Box 162)
  - Still, William Grant, 1926-1963; 3 (Box 162)
  - Stillman College (Box 162)
  - Stokes, Carl B. (Box 163)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher (Box 163)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 1962-1963; 2 (Box 163)
  - Stuyvesant Community Center (Box 163)
  - Sullivan, Maxine (Box 163)
  - Sullivan, Noel (Box 163)
  - Swanson, Howard (Box 163)
  - Sydnor, Earl (Box 163)
  - Talladega College (Box 164)
  - Tanner, Henry O. (Box 164)
  - Tarry, Ellen (Box 164)
  - Tatum, Art (Box 164)
  - Taylor, Billy (Box 164)
  - Taylor, Clarice (Box 164)
  - Teachers Union of the City of New York, 1950-1962; 3 (Box 164)
  - Teer, Barbara Ann (Box 164)
  - Tennessee A & I State University (Box 164)
  - Terrell, Mary Church (Box 164)
  - Thigpen, Helen (Box 164)
  - Third World Press (Box 164)
  - Thomas, Alma (Box 165)
  - Thomas, John (Box 165)
  - Thomas, Piri (Box 165)
  - Thurman, Wallace (Box 165)
  - Thompson, Bob (Box 165)
  - Tobias, Channing H. (Box 165)
  - Tolson, Melvin B. (Box 165)
  - Torchlight Productions, Inc. (Box 165)
  - Trotman, Doris (Box 165)
  - Truth, Sojourner (Box 165)
  - Tubman, Harriet (Box 165)
  - Tucker, Lorenzo (Box 165)
  - Turner, Nat (Box 165)
  - Tuskegee Institute, 1915-1960; 3 (Box 165)
  - Tutuola, Amos (Box 166)
  - Tyler, Veronica (Box 166)
  - Tynes, Margaret, 1951-1961; 4 (Box 166)
  - Tyson, Cicely, 1962-1973; 2 (Box 166)
  - Uggams, Leslie, 1961-1969; 3 (Box 167)
  - United Action for a Free Indonesia (Box 167)
  - United Negro College Fund
    - General, 1944-1974; 5 (Box 167)
    - General (continued), 1974 (Box 168)
    - Creative Writing Contest, 3 (Box 168)
  - United Song Writers (Box 168)
  - U.S. Congress - House Congressional Black Caucus (Box 168)
  - Van Der Zee, James (Box 168)
  - Vanguard League (Box 168)
  - Van Peebles, Melvin (Box 168)
  - Van Vechten, Carl (Box 168)
  - Vaughan, Sarah (Box 168)
  - Vereen, Ben (Box 169)
  - Verrett-Carter, Shirley, 1958-1970; 3 (Box 169)
  - Vodery, Will H. (Box 169)
  - WLIB (New York City) (Box 169)
  - Wadleigh High School (New York City) (Box 169)
  - Walcott, Derek (Box 169)
  - Walcott, Jersey Joe (Box 169)
  - Walker, Alice (Box 169)
  - Walker, Mme. C. J., 2 (Box 169)
  - Walker, George (Box 170)
  - Walker, Joseph A. (Box 170)
  - Walker, Maggie L. (Box 170)
  - Walker, Margaret (Box 170)
  - Waller, Thomas (Fats) (Box 170)
  - Walrond, Eric (Box 170)
  - Walton, Judith (Box 170)
  - War Resisters League (Box 170)
  - Ward, Clara (Box 170)
  - Ward, Douglas Turner (Box 170)
  - Ward, Theodore (Box 170)
  - Warfield, William, 1949-1956; 2 (Box 170)
  - Warfield, William (continued), 1957-1965; 2 (Box 171)
  - Waring, J. Waties (Box 171)
  - Warwick, Dionne (Box 171)
  - Washington, Booker T., 1904-1940; 2 (Box 171)
  - Washington, Dinah (Box 171)
  - Watermargin, Inc. (Box 171)
  - Waters, Ethel, 1926-1933; 2 (Box 171)
  - Waters, Ethel (continued), 1934-1967; 8 (Box 172)
  - Watts, Andre, 1963-1974; 3 (Box 173)
  - Weaver, Robert C. (Box 173)
  - Welch, Elisabeth (Box 173)
  - Wendall, Bruce (Box 173)
  - Wesley, Charles H. (Box 173)
  - West, Lucretia (Box 173)
  - Wheatley, Phillis (Box 173)
  - Whipper, Leigh (Box 173)
  - Whitaker, R. V. (Box 173)
  - White, Carl Darrow (Box 173)
  - White, Charles (Box 173)
  - White, Clarence Cameron (Box 173)
  - White, Jane, 1942-1961; 2 (Box 173)
  - White, Josh, 1944-1957; 2 (Box 174)
  - White, Poppy Cannon, 1949-1975, undated; 2 (Box 174)
  - White, Walter, 1922-1950; 5 (Box 174)
  - White, Walter (continued), 1951-1956, undated; 7 (Box 175)
  - Who's Who in Colored America (Box 175)
  - Who's Who in Harlem (Box 175)
  - Wideman, John Edgar (Box 175)
  - Wilkins, Roy, 1932-1964 (Box 175)
  - Wilkins, Roy (continued), 1965-1970; 7 (Box 176)
  - Wilkins, Roy (continued), 1971-1975; 5 (Box 177)
  - Williams, Bert (Box 177)
  - Williams, Billy Dee (Box 177)
  - Williams, Camilla, 1944-1954; 2 (Box 177)
  - Williams, Camilla (continued), 1955 (Box 178)
  - Williams, Clarence, III (Box 178)
  - Williams, John A. (Box 178)
  - Williams, Mary Lou (Box 178)
  - Williams, Musa (Box 178)
  - Williams, Paul (Box 178)
  - Williams, Robert F. (Box 178)
  - Williamson, Fred (Box 178)
  - Wilson, Flip (Box 178)
  - Wilson, Frank (Box 178)
  - Wiltwyck School for Boys (Box 178)
  - Winfield, Paul (Box 178)
  - Winters, Lawrence, 1946-1952; 2 (Box 179)
  - The Women (Box 179)
  - Wonder, Stevie (Box 179)
  - Woodruff, Hale (Box 179)
  - Woodson, Carter G. (Box 179)
  - Wright, Charles (Box 179)
  - Workshop for Cultural Democracy (Box 179)
  - Wright, Louis T. (Box 179)
  - Wright, Richard, 1938-1961; 4 (Box 179)
  - Wright, Jane C. (Box 179)
  - Writers War Board (Box 180)
  - Xavier University (Box 180)
  - Yerby, Frank (Box 180)
  - Yergan, Max (Box 180)
  - Yordan, Philip (Box 180)
    Anna Lucasta
  - Young, Whitney, Jr., 1964-1971; 4 (Box 180)
  - Y.M.C.A.
    - General, 1928-1954; 2 (Box 181)
    - Harlem Branch, 1923-1951; 3 (Box 181)
  - Y.W.C.A., 1936-1972; 2 (Box 181)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism (Box 181)
- General Subjects, Series III
  - Africa, 1958-1961; 7 (Box 182)
  - Africa (continued), 1961-1964; 5 (Box 183)
  - Africa (continued), 1924-1968 (Box 184)
  - Africa (continued), 1925-1955; 5 (Box 286)
  - African-American Actors
    - Theater and Entertainment, 1889-1930, undated; 7 (Box 185)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1931-1946; 7 (Box 186)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1947-1953; 6 (Box 187)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1955-1961; 6 (Box 188)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1961-1965; 6 (Box 189)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1968-1975; 4 (Box 190)
    - Theater and Entertainment (continued), 1975-1981; 2 (Box 191)
    - Motion Pictures, 1927-1970; 7 (Box 192)
    - Radio and Television, 1942-1973; 6 (Box 193)
    - Radio and Television (continued), 1973-1978 (Box 194)
  - African-American Agricultural Laborers, 1935-1953; 2 (Box 194)
  - African-American Artists
    - General Information and Group Exhibits, 1918-1936, undated; 4 (Box 194)
    - General Information and Group Exhibits (continued), 1937-1954; 6 (Box 195)
    - General Information and Group Exhibits (continued), 1955-1973; 6 (Box 196)
    - Individual Artists, 5 (Box 197)
    - Individual Artists (continued), 3 (Box 198)
  - African-American Athletes
    - General (Box 198)
    - Baseball, 1938-1972; 5 (Box 199)
    - Basketball, 1946-1972; 3 (Box 200)
    - Boxing, 1924-1963; 3 (Box 200)
    - Boxing (continued), 1964-1968; 3 (Box 201)
    - Football, 1916-1967; 2 (Box 201)
    - Golf (Box 202)
    - Tennis (Box 202)
    - Track, 1931-1967; 3 (Box 202)
    - Miscellaneous sports (Box 202)
  - African-American Authors
    - General Information and Anthologies, 1910-1964; 4 (Box 203)
    - General Information and Anthologies (continued), 1965-1973; 3 (Box 204)
    - Individual Authors (A-Co), 2 (Box 204)
    - Individual Authors (Cr-Maj), 5 (Box 205)
    - Individual Authors (Mak-Z), 5 (Box 206)
  - African-American Communists (Box 207)
  - African-American Criminals, 1902-1964; 4 (Box 207)
  - African-American Firefighters (Box 208)
  - African-American Journalists (Box 208)
  - African-American Judges (Box 208)
  - African-American Lawyers (Box 208)
  - African-American Musicians
    - General, 1894-1952; 6 (Box 209)
    - General (continued), 1953-1959; 4 (Box 210)
    - General (continued), 1960-1964; 6 (Box 211)
    - General (continued), 1965-1972; 4 (Box 212)
    - General (continued), 1972-1974, undated; 6 (Box 213)
  - African-American Musicians
    - General, undated; 2 (Box 214)
    - Individual Musicians (A-Bri-), 3 (Box 214)
    - Individual Musicians (Bro-E), 4 (Box 215)
    - Individual Musicians (F-Ja), 5 (Box 216)
    - Individual Musicians (Je-Mat), 6 (Box 217)
    - Individual Musicians (Mau-Sl), 6 (Box 218)
    - Individual Musicians (Sm-Wh), 6 (Box 219)
    - Individual Musicians (Wi-Z) (Box 220)
    - Composers and Arrangers (Box 220)
    - Conductors (Box 220)
    - Instrumental and Singing Groups, 3 (Box 220)
  - African-American Police (Box 221)
  - African-American Press, 1912-1968; 4 (Box 221)
  - African-American Press (continued), 1969 (Box 222)
  - African-American Scientists (Box 222)
  - African-American Seamen (Box 222)
  - African-American Soldiers, 1908-1957; 5 (Box 222)
  - African-American Soldiers (continued), 1958-1971, undated; 5 (Box 223)
  - African-American Studies, 1938-1969; 2 (Box 224)
  - African-American Women, 2 (Box 224)
  - African-American Youth (Box 224)
  - Bibliography
    - University Place Book Shop Lists, 3 (Box 225)
    - University Place Book Shop Lists (continued), 2 (Box 226)
    - Miscellaneous Booklists and Catalogs, 2 (Box 226)
    - Miscellaneous Booklists and Catalogs (continued), 6 (Box 227)
    - Miscellaneous Booklists and Catalogs (continued), 4 (Box 228)
  - Chicago (Box 229)
  - Civil Rights, 1851-1948; 2 (Box 229)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1949-1959; 5 (Box 230)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1960-1963; 6 (Box 231)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1963-1964; 5 (Box 232)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1964; 5 (Box 233)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1964-1966; 6 (Box 234)
  - Civil Rights (continued), 1967-1971, undated; 5 (Box 235)
  - Dancing, 1928-1968; 6 (Box 236)
  - Economic Conditions, 1904-1971; 4 (Box 237)
  - Education
    - General, undated; 2 (Box 237)
    - General (continued), 1902-1945; 6 (Box 238)
    - General (continued), 1945-1954; 6 (Box 239)
    - General (continued), 1955-1963; 7 (Box 240)
    - General (continued), 1963-1967; 4 (Box 241)
    - General (continued), 1967-1970; 6 (Box 242)
    - General (continued), 1970-1973; 4 (Box 243)
    - Yale University, 1946-1971; 3 (Box 244)
  - Employment, 1906-1967; 5 (Box 245)
  - Employment (continued), 1967-1971; 3 (Box 246)
  - History
    - General, 1865-1949; 3 (Box 246)
    - General (continued), 1950-1968; 5 (Box 247)
    - General (continued), 1968-1980; 4 (Box 248)
    - Life Magazine Series, 1968 (Box 248)
    - "They Had a Dream" - Los Angeles Times Service Biographical Series, 2 (Box 249)
    - Black History Week, 1932-1953; 2 (Box 249)
  - Housing, 1925-1962; 5 (Box 250)
  - Housing (continued), 1963-1967; 2 (Box 251)
  - Languages (Box 251)
  - Library Resources (Box 251)
  - Medical Care (Box 251)
  - Politics and Suffrage, 1885-1964; 6 (Box 252)
  - Politics and Suffrage (continued), 1965-1972; 5 (Box 253)
  - Politics and Suffrage (continued), 1972-1974, undated; 3 (Box 254)
  - Religion
    - General, 1895-1943; 2 (Box 254)
    - General (continued), 1943-1963; 6 (Box 255)
    - General (continued), 1963-1973; 5 (Box 256)
    - General (continued), 1973, undated; 3 (Box 257)
    - "Protestant Church Life" and "Protestant News" (Box 257)
  - Seamen (Box 258)
  - Social Conditions
    - General, 1903-1940, undated; 5 (Box 258)
    - General (continued), 1941-1955; 7 (Box 259)
    - General (continued), 1956-1963; 6 (Box 260)
    - General (continued), 1964-1968; 5 (Box 261)
    - General (continued), 1968-1973; 6 (Box 262)
    - Hotels, Restaurants, and Travel (Box 263)
    - Fashion, Cosmetics, and Beauty Contests, 1930-1972; 4 (Box 263)
    - Folk Spiritualism (Box 263)
  - Social Work, 1922-1956 (Box 263)
  - Social Work (continued), 1957-1964, undated; 4 (Box 264)
  - Societies, etc., 1920-1972; 5 (Box 265)
  - Statistics, Vital (Box 265)
  - African-Americans in Business, 1909-1949; 2 (Box 265)
  - African-Americans in Business (continued), 1950-1972; 3 (Box 266)
  - African-Americans in Literature (A-F), 2 (Box 266)
  - African-Americans in Literature (G-Z), 5 (Box 267)